Siyanda Kopolo

Deaf Software Developer

071 986 4573 SMS ONLY

siyandakopolo2@gmail.com

https://github.com/SKopoloza895

Protea Glen, Soweto, 1819

ABOUT ME

Deaf individual skilled in effective sign language communication during interviews. Completed a 3-year Diploma in Information Technology (Software Development) and pursued self-development at Botlhale Village. Experienced in In-Service Training and IOCO Software Developer Graduate program. Strengthened skills through cloud computing and IT System Support programs. Actively studying Swift-focused App development. Adaptable team player with strong goal-setting, listening, and learning abilities. Embraces challenges with a creative mindset.

EDUCATION

ICT Software Testing NQF L5

iSchool Africa Feb 2023 - Currently

IT System Support NQF L5

SpecCon Holdings (Pty) Ltd June 2022 - April 2023

Cloud Computing (Skills Programme)

Za Wit (Pty) Ltd

March 2021 - Sept 2021

Diploma in Information Technology

Belgium Campus iTversity Jan 2016 - May 2021

Wholesale & Retail Operations NQF L2

Employ & Empower Deaf Pty Ltd
June 2012 - Mar 2014

Certificate in Office Administration

NID College Jan 2010 - Dec 2010

Grade 12

St Thomas Special School Jan 1995 - Dec 2009

SKILLS

- . UIKit Xcode
- · ReactJs
- JavaScript
- · Html & CSS
- Graphic Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer Learnership

June 2022 - April 2023

Digital Academy I Johannesburg

- Work in team and self-manage also willingness to learn new languages programming.
- Build collaborating on a website development team.
- · Design and build websites using simple HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Techniques for logical problem solving and error detection

Software Developer Graduate

Feb 2020 - Jan 2021

Botlhale Village I Pretoria North

- · Perform self-development and advancement.
- · Researched and developed new technology designs.
- · Work as a team on developing an interactive and dynamic website

Software Developer In-Service Training

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Botlhale Village | Pretoria North

- Html5 and CSS3 supported project managers in determining milestones and project scope
- Created interactive websites with software development department using backend and frontend framework
- Lifecycle (SDLC) created spreadsheets using Microsoft Excel for daily, weekly
 and monthly reporting contributing as team leader and member learning from
 working with experienced software developers.

Retailer Operations Learnership

June 2012 - March 2014

CheckerHyper | Edenvale

- Process Payments and purchases on the POS system
- · Maintaining and controlling stock losses
- Maintain detailed records concerning defective goods, return goods to vendors, and provide follow-up to obtain replacement or credit.

REFERENCES

Mr Edward van Niekerk

Sign Language Interprete / Senior Lecturer

Phone: 083 775 4532

Email: edward@belgiumcampus.ac.za

Chelsea Williamson

Programme Manager

Phone: 084 995 7804

Email: chelsea.williamson@ischoolafrica

.com